

# Preeti Kumari

Queue Manager



Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Email: Preetipeace18@gmail.com

Mob.: 9035435026

An IT professional with 6 years of experience in Queue and Incident Managment. Currently serving as Queue Manager for Microsoft client. I have worked with several amazing companies which helped me explore my potential and ethics to become a dedicated, self-motivated person. Companies like Infosys, Ericsson, Unisys, Flipkart has taught me a lot in molding me what I'm today which I'm truly grateful about. I'm looking forward to being a part of renowned organization to effectively manage different parts in the organization & to work towards the growth of the organization contributing my efforts for new learnings, experience and my personal growth as well:)

## **Work Experience**

**Queue Manager** 



Vendor Company: TeamWare Solutions (A division of Quantum Leap Consulting Pvt. Ltd)

Client: Microsoft Corporation

August 2021 - February 2023

Duty Manager for Azure Cybersecurity POD

- · Constantly and proactively check incoming volume and engage and distribute the respective volume to the available resource pool
- · Prioritize critical escalation and ensure timely assignment of incoming workload
- · Ensure proper capacity planning according to the requirements of the business
- · Optimize schedule for adequate workload distribution
- · Proactively plan for expected events while also ensuring BCP requirements are met.
- · Handling unplanned OOFs Recording, Customer contact, arranging resources if required
- · Reporting Queue Status at end of the day, Queue wise Unplanned OOF %, Tool Outages, and other anomalies impacting the SLA's and Customer Experience.
- · Act as a queue supervisor for queues, including cross-site, time-zone, managed queues. This shall include issue assignment, follow-up and making customer call downs for issue clarification, expectation setting.
- · Quality assurance Case review quality reviewing incoming case and tasks (Region/POD specific) ##TOOLS: CASEBUDDY, DFM, DFM EU, RAVE, WFM, CASE MANAGER 2.0, CRM BOT Skills: Queue Management · Escalations Management · Team Management · Customer Experience · Communication · IT Operations · Operations Management · Teamwork.

Service Delivery Associate 2:

Vendor Company: E Team Consulting Pvt. Ltd

Client: Unisys

April 2019 - December 2019

Initiate Skype meeting with the engineers and leads of the region for distribution of tickets and queries.

Sending daily ticket reports to all the field engineers and concerned leaders and managers including my team.

Perform a daily review of pending tickets and help them with taking the necessary actions.

Correct assignment of tickets based on priority,

Replying to emails for progress of tickets to team

Resolving queries of field engineers.

Making sure that field engineers are closing tickets within SLA with proper updates. Initiate Skype meeting with the engineers and leads of the region for distribution of tickets and queries.

Sending daily ticket reports to all the field engineers and concerned leaders and managers including my team.

Perform a daily review of pending tickets and help them with taking the necessary actions.

Correct assignment of tickets based on priority,

Replying to emails for progress of tickets to team

Resolving queries of field engineers.

Making sure that field engineers are closing tickets within SLA with proper updates

##TOOLS: Click Schedule Software##Initiate Skype meeting with the engineers and leads of the region for distribution of tickets and queries. Sending daily ticket reports to all the field engineers and concerned leads and managers reports, including my team. Perform a daily review of pending tickets and help them with taking the necessary actions. Correct assignment of tickets based on priority, replying to emails for progress of tickets to team, resolving queries of field engineer. Making sure that field engineers are closing tickets within SLA with proper updates. Initiate meetings with the engineers and leaders of the region for distribution of tickets and queries. Sending daily ticket reports to all the field engineers and concerned leads and managers reports, including my team. Perform a daily review of pending tickets and help them with taking the necessary actions. Correct assignment of tickets based on priority, replying to emails for progress of tickets to team resolving queries of field engineer. Making sure that field engineers are closing tickets within SLA with proper updates

##TOOLS: Click Schedule Software

##Skills: Communication · IT Operations · Operations Management · Teamwork.

#### Incident Management coordinator/ Dispatch Engineer

#### • Ericsson India Global Services Pvt. Ltd

November 2015 - December 2017

Accountable to ensure ticket management is timely and accurate

Under the guidance of the Major Incident Manager, assemble the appropriate recovery teams as per outage demand.

Perform a daily review of pending tickets and help them with taking the necessary actions.

Generate periodic reports on the status of tickets which require tracking and follow-up.

Ensure the post-Major Incident activities are completed by the respective owners.

Take ownership of cross-team communication when multiple teams are involved in the resolution of the ticket.

Act as a backup to the Major Incident Manager when required and incident follow-ups where required.

Once the agreed level of competency is achieved, we take ownership of major incidents under the guidance of a Major Incident Manager.

Ensures close collaboration, coordination and synchronization with the operational Team Leads/Delivery Teams for major incidents.

##TOOLS: Click Schedule Software, IPCM, SRMS##Accountable to ensure Ticket Management is timely and accurate. Under the guidance of the Major Incident Manager, assemble the appropriate recovery teams as per outage demand. Perform a daily review of pending tickets and help them with taking the necessary actions. Generate periodic reports on the status of tickets which require tracking and follow-up. Ensure the post-Major Incident activities are completed by the respective owners. Take ownership of cross-team communication when multiple teams are involved in the resolution of the ticket. Act as a backup to the Major Incident Manager when required and incident follow-ups were required. Once the agreed level of

competency is achieved, you take ownership of major incidents under the guidance of a Major Incident Manager. Ensures close collaboration, coordination and synchronization with Operational Team Leads/Delivery Teams for major incidents. ##TOOLS: Click Schedule Software, IPCM, SRMS##

Skills: Service Desk · Communication · IT Operations · Customer Service · Operations Management · Teamwork.

### Senior Customer Support Executive



### • Infosys Limited

November 2013 - November 2015

Handling Escalations for L2 level

Supporting UK customers with their PSTN line related issues and troubleshooting

Working on Service Requests and closing them once completed

Liaising with internal departments to fetch daily updates on customer's PSTN fault

Updating relevant information on Siebel (One view) including customer profile information

Keeping customers informed about the status of their PSTN service status and arranging follow-ups

Booking and rescheduling appointments based on customer needs and sending confirmation via

Email and text

Tracking daily productivity in Form wise

##TOOLS: WFM TOOL (one view Siebel), PRODUCTIVITY TRACKER, UTXT##Handling Escalations for L2 level Supporting UK customers with their PSTN line related issues and troubleshooting Working on Service Requests and closing them once completed Liaising with internal departments to fetch daily updates on customer's PSTN fault Updating relevant information on Siebel (One view) including customer profile information Keeping customers informed about the status of their PSTN service status and arranging follow-ups Booking and rescheduling appointments based on customer needs and sending confirmation via email and text Tracking daily productivity on Form wise .

##TOOLS: WFM TOOL (one view Siebel), PRODUCTIVITY TRACKER, UTXT##

 $Skills: Service\ Desk\cdot Communication\cdot IT\ Operations\cdot Troubleshooting\cdot Customer\ Service\cdot Teamwork.$ 

### Education



Visvesvaraya Technological University (VTU)

2006 - 2010

B.E EEE



Passed 12th From CBSE Board Delhi

2004 - 2006

Class XII,PCM



Passed 10th From CBSE Board

2003 - 2004

Class X

### Skills

## Languages

- Word
- Communication
- Ms. Excel
- Microsoft Office
- Management Skills
- Service Desk

• English — Professional

- IT Operations
- Operations Management
- Queue Management
- Escalations Management
- Teamwork & Collaboration
- Quick Learner

Powered by **CakeResume**